<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="36"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Faculty Of Pharmacy Mansoura National University



                                ﺔـﻴﻠﻫﻷﺍ ﺓﺭﻮـﺼﻨﻤﻟﺍ ﺔـﻌـﻣﺎﺟ - ﺔـﻟﺪــﻴﺼﻟﺍ ﺔـﻴﻠﻛ

                                FACULTY OF PHARMACY - MANSOURA NATIONAL UNIVERSITY


                                           FACULTY OF PHARMACY
                                  NEWSLETTER







                                  Under Patronage of University President
                                          Prof. Cherif Khater



















































                    EDITOR-IN-CHIEF                                                        EDITOR
           Assoc. Prof. Ahmed R. ElSheakh                                            Dr. Bassant Maher


                                                    Vol. 1 - Issue 1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[1.Global Trends 2023


                                      The History Repeats Itself!                                    08


                                      Top 10 Pharma Industry Trends & innovations in                 10
                                      2023

                       Table of Contents
                                    2.On Fire, From the Top FDA’s Actions in 2023

                                      FDA’s Decision to Withdraw Approval of Makena                  14


                                      FDA approves first over-the-counter Narcan                     14


                                      FDA authorizes first at-home combo flu/Covid test              15


                                      First Oral Treatment for Anemia Caused by Chron-
                                      ic Kidney Disease                                              15

                                      Novel Drug Approvals for 2023                                  16


                                      FDA Expands Atogepant Approval                                 17


                                    3.Faculty Activities & Achievements

                                      Student Scientific Team’s Success Journey                      20


                                      Pharmacovigilance awareness day                                24


                                      The first student scientific day                               25


                                      Student Activities in the Pharmacognosy Term II,               26
                                      2022/2023

                                      Signed protocols and partnerships                              27


                                    4.Student Honor Board


                                      The top ten ranked students                                    30

                                      Ramadan Religious Competition                                  30


                                      Student Union                                                  31


                                    5.Editorial Board                                                32


                                    6. Acknowledgment                                                33

                                    7.Faculty Strategy                                               34]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[President






                                                              Speech








              Dear Pharmacy Community,



              I am thrilled to announce the launch of the first volume of our pharmacy newsletter at Mansoura
              National University, to share with you the exciting news, achievement and student participations .
              In this 1st  issue of our Newsletter, we represent our commitment to sharing the important work
              being done by our staff and students with a wider audience. With each issue, we hope to showcase
              the incredible research, teaching, and patient care being done by our students, and staff.
              In this first issue, you will find articles on a range of topics, including updates on groundbreaking
              topics,  achievements of faculty members and students, and news on upcoming events and initiatives.

              I encourage you to read through this issue and to share it with your colleagues and friends.
              By doing so, you are helping to spread awareness of the important work being done by our pharmacy
              staff and students to support our mission of excellence in education and research.
              Thank you for your continued dedication to the field of pharmacy, and I look forward to the many
              exciting accomplishments we will achieve together in the future.



              Sincerely,



              Prof. Cherif Khater

              University President]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Program




                                                              Director




                                                              Speech








             Dear colleagues,



             We are pleased to welcome you all to our faculty Newsletter. As we approach the end of our first
             academic year, we are proud to share with you the many accomplishments and successes of our
             students, faculty, and staff.

             As Editor-in-Chief, I am honored to lead the publication of this Newsletter and provide a platform
             for our faculty community to share their stories and achievements. This year, we have received a
             record number of submissions, which is a testament to the incredible work and dedication of our
             students and faculty.

             As Program Director, I want to express my gratitude to our outstanding faculty members who have
             gone above and beyond to support our students during these challenging times. Their commitment
             to teaching and service has made a positive impact on the lives of our students and the wider
             community.

             In  this  Newsletter,  you  will  find  articles  and  updates  on  our  academic  programs,  community
             outreach, and student activities. We hope that you will find these stories inspiring and informative,
             and that they will showcase the many achievements of our faculty community.

             Once again, thank you for your contributions to this Newsletter, and we look forward to another
             successful year ahead.



             Sincerely,



             Ahmed R ElSheakh]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Chapter I]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Global







                                            Trends







                                                  2023]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Chapter I


             The History Repeats Itself !

             «Will artificial intelligence be the mirror of the industrial revolution attack?»
















             Artificial intelligence (AI) has gained recent    medicine,  imaging  analysis,  drug  discovery,
             public prominence with the release of deep-       telemedicine,  and  surgical  support.
             learning  models  that  can  generate  anything   More recently, AI has been used in the writing
             from art to term papers with minimal human        process  of  research  papers.  Subsequently,  a
             intervention. The growth of this science and its   number of journals added specific instructions
             applications in all areas of life is accelerating in   that needed to be followed in their guide for
             an unprecedented way, so that it now touches      authors› sections for those who use generative
             every aspect of our lives, and its cognitive and   AI  and  AI-assisted  technologies  in  their
             absorptive capabilities are qualified to exceed   writing  process.  Additionally,  using  these
             human  capabilities.  On  the  other  hand,  they   technologies  in  a  research  paper  has  been
             increase the possibility of risks that may force   added to be checked in the plagiarism checker
             us to have undesirable effects. If AI can bring   engines.
             good consequences, then it can likewise have
             dire  ones  for  human  societies,  environment,
             ecosystems, human life, and even the human
             mind, given the new ways which affect how
             people think, interact, and make decisions.

             As  regards  to  using  AI  applications  in
             medical  and  pharmacy  fields,  it  appears  as
             one  in  which  there  is  tremendous  potential
             along  with  equally  substantial  challenges.
             For example, it has been used for diagnostic
             support,  predictive  analytics,  personalized

             The Question here,


             Will all people cope blindingly with these technologies in all their daily life?
             The other face of many scientists and public figures opinions


             A  group  of  scientists  drafted  an  open  letter   been produced so far and make sure it does
             that was successively approved and signed by      not harm humanity before going beyond that.
             many scientists and public figures, including     And if this step is not done, they will call on
             Elon  Musk,  who  is  one  of  Open  AI’s  co-    governments  to  intervene  quickly  to  impose
             founders,  proposing  to  stop  developing        this  stop. They  also  call  on  laboratories  and
             software  experiments  more  powerful  than       experts  to  take  advantage  of  this  downtime
             GPT-4 (the latest version of the large language   to  develop  a  set  of  safety  agreements  that
             model  software  developed  by  U.S.  startup     regulate the development of AI systems so that
             Open AI) for six months to review what has        they  are  supervised  and  monitored  by  other


             8    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Global Trends 2023


             independent experts. However, this does not       Finally, what is your opinion?
             mean a complete cessation of the development      Will  you  support  using  AI  in  all  our  fields
             of  all  forms  of  AI  in  general,  but  only  the   without  restrictions?
             cessation of the frantic race to produce systems
             whose  potential  is  unpredictable  .            Or, you will disagree it totally as some workers
                                               [1]
                                                               feared in the past?
             Also, some Arab scholars and professors have
             designed their own an open letter to be signed    Or, you will go to sign this commitment?
             also  .
                  [2]














                       Captured on 12th April, 2023            For more details check the following:
             The Director-General of UNESCO responded
             to  this  letter  by  appealing  to  the  world’s   1.https://futureoflife.org/open-letter/pause-giant-ai-
                                                               experiments
             governments  to  abide  by  the  November
             2021  Ethical  Recommendation  for Artificial     2.https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_-
                                                               qKOmhcve9GPry9yFsmoS-9joSyeqO9Lkd429gCLtA/
             Intelligence,  which  has  been  approved  by     edit?usp=sharing
             every  country  in  the  world   [3,4] . Also,  TIME   3.https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/artificial-
             magazine  published  an  article  saying  that    intelligence-unesco-calls-all-governments-implement-
             six  months  is  not  enough  and  suggesting  a   global-ethical-framework-without
             complete halt to these advanced experiments       4. https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/
             [5] .                                             pf0000380455_ara
             Concerning some people’s fear of losing their     5.https://time.com/6266923/ai-eliezer-yudkowsky-
             traditional jobs with these inserted technologies,   open-letter-not-enough/
             these  responses  are  natural  and  expected,
             as the human outstanding doubt of any new
             aspects that might replace humanity. And what
             happened  in  18-19   centuries,  particularly
                                 th
             during the first industrial revolution can teach
             us about the possible coming upset in the job
             market  with AI  use,  as  workers  at  this  time         1                         2
             had the experience of being suddenly thrown
             out  of  their  jobs  by  automation.  But  rather
             than accept it, they fought back, attacked, and
             destroyed  machines.
             But  it  is  expected  that  people  will  adapt  to
             these  changes  and  technologies  that  looked            3                         4
             strange  at  the  beginning,  particularly  when
             they  could  find  the  pros  of  these  issues  in
             saving  time  and  effort  with  some  accurate
             outcomes. Additionally, new job opportunities
             will be created for those who were able to take
             advantage  of  AI  technologies.
                                                                                     5

                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Chapter I


             Top 10 Pharma Industry Trends & Innovations in 2023

             Keep tracking and cope with the job opportunities and facilities in pharmacy

             field that you may ignore.
                 Data from StartUs are summarized and illustrated as the following:

             1. Artificial Intelligence                        6. Blockchain

             Pangaea Data – Patient Cohort Identification:     PharmaTrace  –  Smart  Contracts:  offers  a
             is  a  British  startup  that  uses  unsupervised   blockchain-based ecosystem to secure data and
             AI algorithms to identify patient cohorts for     deploy smart contracts in the pharmaceutical
             drug discovery, clinical trials, and real-world   industry.
             evidence  (RWE)  studies.                         Veratrak  –  Pharma  Supply  Chain:  offers  a

             InVivo  AI  –  Drug  Discovery:  for  drug        blockchain-based  document  collaboration
             discovery.                                        and  workflow  management  platform  for  the

             2. Big Data & Analytics                           pharmaceutical  supply  chain.

             Pryml  –  Secure  Data  Collaboration:  creates   7. Extended Reality (XR)
             a  synthetic  version  of  the  confidential  data   Nanome  –  VR  Collaboration  Tool:  offers
             available  with  pharmaceutical  companies.       virtual reality collaboration tools for atomic,

             Pomicell  –  In-Silico  Modeling:  for  big  data   molecular,  and  protein  visualization.
             analytics  in  pharmaceutical  research  and      Goodly Innovations – AR Suite: an augmented
             development  (R&D).                               reality  suite  for  pharma  and  biopharma

             3. Flexible Production                            manufacturing.
             Cellexus  –  Single-Use  Bioreactor:  makes       8. Real-World Data
             single-use  airlift  bioreactor  systems.  The    Graticule – Unstructured Patient Data: makes
             startup’s  patented  airlift  technology  uses    use of clinical notes, free text, and images, as
             bubbles instead of mechanical mixing to move      well as non-clinical data for data completeness.
             cells  and  nutrients.                            OncoChain  –  Oncological  Data:  offers  a

             Secoya     Technologies     –     Continuous      research  platform  based  on  a  de-identified
             Manufacturing  Optimisation:  tailoring  the      real-world  oncological  patient  database.
             continuous manufacturing process equipment        9. Digital Therapeutics
             down  to  the  ideal  scale.

             4. Precision Medicine                             Cognivive  –  Neuro-Rehabilitation:  offers
                                                               evidence-based  digital  therapeutics  for  the
             ExactCure  –  Drug  Exposure  Model:  for         treatment  of  neurocognitive  and  neuromotor
             simulating the effects of drugs in a patient’s    impairments.
             body  based  on  personal  characteristics.       Dopavision – Eye Treatment: a smartphone-
             Tepthera  –  Individualized  Cancer  Vaccine:     based  digital  therapeutic  for  myopia.
             offers   platform    technologies   for   the     10. Curative Therapies
             identification  of  T  cell  antigens.
                                                               Mogrify – Cell Therapy: a proprietary direct
             5. Additive Manufacturing                         cellular  conversion  platform  to  transmogrify

             FabRx – Printed Pill: a 3D printer for making     any mature human cells.
             personalized  pills  that  uses  proprietary      Lacerta  Therapeutics  –  Gene  Therapy:  a
             technology  for  direct  powder  extrusion.       clinical-stage  gene  therapy  startup  working
             Frontier  Bio  –  Tissue  Bioprinter:  a  3D      on  cures  for  the  central  nervous  system  and
             bioprinter  for  making  human  tissues.          lysosomal  storage  diseases.


             10   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Global Trends 2023













































                      Top 10 Innovation trends on pharma industry

                                Top 10 innovation trends and thier impact on the pharma industry


                            21%                                                                Artificial Intelligence
                                               15%                                             Big Data & Analytics

                                                     13%                                       Flexible Production

                                                                  9%                           Precision Medicine

                                                                  9%                           Additive Manufacturing
                                                                  9%                           Blockchain

                                                                        7%                     Extended Reality (XR)

                                                                           6%                  Real-World Data
                                                                           6%                  Digital Therapeutics

                                                                               5%              Curative Therapies




             Reference:

             https://www.startus-insights.com/innovators-guide/top-
             10-pharma-industry-trends-innovations-in-2021/






                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Chapter II]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[On Fire





                    From the top FDA’s





                    actions in 2023]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Chapter II

             FDA’s decision to withdraw                        that  this  serious  condition  has  a  disparate

             approval  of  Makena                              impact  on  communities  of  color,  especially
                                                               Black  women,”  FDA  Commissioner  Robert
                                                               M. Califf, MD, said in a statement about the
                                                               decision.

                                                               Risks  associated  with  the  drug  include
                                                               thromboembolic        disorders,     allergic
                                                               reactions,  decreased  glucose  tolerance,  and
                                                               fluid  retention,  regulators  have  noted.  The
                                                               agency acknowledged that some supplies of
                                                               the  product  have  already  been  distributed.
                                                               Patients  with  questions  should  talk  to  their
             The  US  Food  and  Drug  Administration          healthcare  provider,  the  FDA  advised.
             (FDA)  announced  on April  6,  2023,  that  it   Reference:
             has decided to withdraw approval of Makena
             and  its  generic  versions.                      https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-
                                                               announcements/fda-commissioner-and-
             Makena  is  a  progestin  that  was  approved     chief-scientist-announce-decision-withdraw-
             in  2011  to  reduce  the  risk  of  preterm  birth   approval-makena
             in  women  with  a  previous  spontaneous
             preterm  birth.  The  treatment  had  been
             approved  under  an  accelerated  pathway
             based on a determination that the sponsor had
             demonstrated a drug effect on an intermediate
             clinical endpoint that was reasonably likely to
             predict clinical benefit. The agency’s approval
             included  a  requirement  that  the  sponsor
             conduct a post-marketing confirmatory study.
             In the years since Makena was approved, the       FDA approves first over-the-
             drug’s  sponsor  Covis  says,  about  350,000     counter Narcan
             women have been treated with it. But a large
             2019  study  failed  to  show  that  it  actually
             prevented  preterm  birth.  Subsequently,  the
             agency  proposed  withdrawing  the  drug  in
             2020,  but  Covis  requested  a  hearing  on
             the  decision,  and  that  meeting  was  held  in
             October  2022.

             The  FDA  commissioner  and  chief  scientist
             subsequently reviewed the submitted reports,
             comments,  and  transcripts,  and  made  the
             decision  to  withdraw  the  drug.  “Effective
             today, Makena and its generics are no longer
             approved and cannot lawfully be distributed
             in  interstate  commerce,”  the  agency  said.
             “It  is  tragic  that  the  scientific  research  and
             medical  communities  have  not  yet  found  a    On  29   March  2023,  the  FDA  approved
                                                                       th
             treatment shown to be effective in preventing     Narcan,  an  opioid  overdose  reversal  drug,
             preterm  birth  and  improving  neonatal          to  be  sold  without  a  prescription.  Narcan
             outcomes — particularly in light of the fact      can now be sold in gas stations, convenience


             14    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[On Fire

             stores and grocery stores. The approval marks     First oral treatment for
             the first time any form of naloxone will be
             available  without  a  prescription  that  will   Anemia caused by Chronic
             increase  the  number  of  locations  where  it’s   Kidney Disease
             available  and  help  reduce  opioid  overdose
             deaths. The drug, which first received FDA
             approval in 1971, was originally an injection.
             The  FDA  approved  the  inhaled  nasal  spray
             version, more commonly known as Narcan,
             in  2015.  It  contains  4  mg  of  naloxone  that
             can be sprayed into the nose like a common
             allergy  medication.

             Reference:
             https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-
             announcements/fda-approves-first-over-
             counter-naloxone-nasal-spray
                                                               The  FDA  on  1     February  2023  approved
                                                                                st
                                                               Jesduvroq  tablets  (daprodustat)  as  the  first
                                                               oral treatment for anemia (decreased number
                                                               of red blood cells) caused by chronic kidney
                                                               disease  for  adults  who  have  been  receiving
                                                               dialysis for at least four months. Jesduvroq
                                                               is not approved for patients who are not on
                                                               dialysis.

             FDA authorizes first at-home
             combo flu/Covid test                              Reference:

                                                               https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-
             The FDA on 24  February 2023, authorized          announcements/fda-approves-first-oral-
                              th
             emergency  use  of  the  first  over-the-counter   treatment-anemia-caused-chronic-kidney-
             test  that  can  detect  both  Covid-19  and  flu.   disease-adults-dialysis
             The single-use test, made by Lucira Health,
             is  able  to  differentiate  between  influenza A
             and  B  as  well  as  Covid.  It  takes  about  30
             minutes  to  get  results  from  a  self-collected
             nasal  swab.

             Reference:

             https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-
             announcements/fda-authorizes-first-over-
             counter-home-test-detect-both-influenza-
             and-covid-19-viruses














                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Chapter II

             Novel Drug Approvals for 2023


             Innovative drugs often mean new treatment options for patients and advances in health care.
             Each year, FDA’s Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER) approves a wide range of
             new drugs and biological products. Some of these products have never been used in clinical
             practice. Below is a listing of new molecular entities and new therapeutic biological products
             that CDER approved in 2023.


                               Active      Approval
               Drug Name                                       FDA-approved use on approval date*
                             Ingredient      Date

              Leqembi      lecanemab-irmb 1/6/2023   To treat Alzheimer’s diseasePress Release

                                                     To improve glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes
              Brenzavvy      bexagliflozin  1/20/2023  mellitus as an adjunct to diet and exercise


                                                     To treat relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma in adults
              Jaypirca       pirtobrutinib  1/27/2023 who have had at least two lines of systemic therapy, including a
                                                     BTK inhibitor

                                                     To treat estrogen receptor-positive, human epidermal growth
                                                     factor receptor 2-negative, ESR1-mutated, advanced or meta-
              Orserdu         elacestrant  1/27/2023  static breast cancer with disease progression following at least

                                                     one line of endocrine therapy

                                                     To treat anemia caused by chronic kidney disease for adults on
              Jesduvroq      daprodustat   2/1/2023  dialysis for at least four monthsPress Release



              Lamzede        velmanase al-  2/16/2023  To treat non-central nervous system manifestations of al-
                                                     pha-mannosidosis
                               fa-tycv
                                                     To reduce proteinuria in adults with primary immunoglobulin
              Filspari        sparsentan   2/17/2023
                                                     A nephropathy at risk of rapid disease progression
              Skyclarys     omaveloxolone 2/28/2023  To treat Friedrich’s ataxia

              Zavzpret        zavegepant   3/9/2023  To treat migraine

              Daybue          trofinetide  3/10/2023  To treat Rett syndrome

                            retifanlimab-dl-         To treat metastatic or recurrent locally advanced Merkel cell
              Zynyz                        3/22/2023
                                 wr                  carcinoma

              Rezzayo         rezafungin   3/22/2023  To treat candidemia and invasive candidiasis

              Joenja          leniolisib   3/24/2023  To treat activated phosphoinositide 3-kinase delta syndrome


             Reference:

             https://www.fda.gov/drugs/new-drugs-fda-cders-
             new-molecular-entities-and-new-therapeutic-
             biological-products/novel-drug-approvals-2023





             16    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[On Fire

              FDA  Expands Atogepant Approval  to  Include  Chronic  Mi-

              graine



             The  FDA  has  approved  an  expanded             significant reduction from baseline in mean
             indication  for  atogepant  (Qulipta,  Abbvie)    monthly  migraine  days  with  atogepant
             to  include  prevention  of  chronic  migraine    compared  with  placebo  across  the  12-
             in adults. The approval makes atogepant the       week  treatment  period.  Treatment  with
             first,  and  only,  oral  calcitonin  gene-related   atogepant also led to statistically significant
             peptide (CGRP) receptor antagonist approved       improvements in all six secondary endpoints,
             to  prevent  migraine  across  frequencies,       including  the  proportion  of  patients  that
             including  episodic  and  chronic.                achieved  at  least  a  50%  reduction  in  mean
                                                               monthly migraine days across 12 weeks and
             The  FDA  initially  approved  atogepant  in      improvements  in  function  and  reduction  in
             2021  for  prevention  of  episodic  migraine     activity  impairment  due  to  migraine.
             in  adults.  Once-daily  atogepant  is  available
             in  three  doses  —  10  mg,  30  mg,  and  60    The  overall  safety  profile  of  atogepant  is
             mg — for prevention of episodic migraine.         consistent with the episodic migraine patient
             However, only the 60 mg dose of medication        population,  with  the  most  common  adverse
             is  indicated  for  the  preventive  treatment  of   events  including  constipation,  nausea,  and
             chronic migraine.                                 fatigue/sleepiness.  The  FDA  approval  is  an
                                                               important  milestone,  providing  those  most

             This expanded indication is based on positive     impacted by migraine with a new, safe, and
             results of the phase 3 PROGRESS trial that        effective  treatment  option  in  a  convenient,
             met  the  primary  endpoint  of  statistically    once-daily  pill.



































              Reference:

              https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/991371








                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Chapter III]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Activities & Achievements]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Chapter III




             Student Scientific Team’s Success Journey

             The first attended conference with its achievements &

             winning ranks



















             The  student  scientific  team  at  the  Faculty   6.Participation in medical convoys and other
             of  Pharmacy,  Mansoura  National  University        community services.
             (MNU)  was  established  in  February  2023       The first task of the team was to participate
             under the supervision of Assoc. Prof. Ahmed       with  scientific  topics  and  research  articles
             Ramadan ElSheakh - acting dean of the college     in  the 4   student  conference  that  was  held
                                                                       th
             - and Dr. Bassant Maher - coordinator of student   at the  Delta  University  for Science  and
             scientific training - to be the first activity in   Technology on March 12 , 2023 that covered
                                                                                        th
             the university that directs students to deal with   student  participation  from  different  colleges
             practical scientific life in a realistic way and   around the Egyptian Republic. This task was
             give  them  the  opportunity  to  participate  in   important, interesting, but challenging as the
             events and research developments inside and       limited time and experience of the students in
             outside the university, which is Keeping pace     their  first  year  at  the  pharmacy  colleges.
             with  Egypt’s  vision  2030,  especially  in  its
             axis of innovation, knowledge, and scientific     While and according to the established plan,
             research.                                         periodic  meetings,  well-done  preparation,
                                                               and  ambitious  brilliant  students,  the  task
             From the activities and responsibilities of the   was performed in a professional way and the
             students in this team:                            students won two places from all ones at the
              1.Organizing  scientific  conferences,  events,   conference.
                and  seminars.

              2.Participation  in  scientific  conferences
                through presentations or posters of scientific
                research,  or  other  active  participation.

              3.Participation in the college’s research plans.
              4.Conducting  their  own  scientific  research
                with  the  capability  of  publishing  them.
              5.Aware and educate colleagues
                and community with medical and
                pharmaceutical topics through videos,
                brochures, and other publishing materials.





             20    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Activities & Achievements


































                 MNU Pharmacy scientific students who won places at the conference


                          2  place for the best                           Outstanding participation
                           nd
                           oral presentation                             with oral presentation place






                           Aseel Mohammed                                       Shahd Ahmed

                              Israa nasser                                      Ghada Gamal
                           Sara Mohammed                                       Yasmeen Ahmed
                          Omnia mohammed                                         Hana Tarek
                            Raghad kandil                                      Hanin Ibrahim

                             Reham ahmed                                      Shrook Mohamed































                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Chapter III





























































































             22    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Activities & Achievements





























































































                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Chapter III

             Pharmacovigilance Awareness Day


             On Tuesday, March 14  2023, the Faculty of Pharmacy MNU organized a scientific day entitled
                                    th
             “Pharmacovigilance Awareness Day”.

             The activities of this day started with a presentation introduced by Dr. Bassant Maher about the
             concept of pharmacovigilance (PV), its importance, why we need PV, and the responsibility of
             the healthcare providers for detecting and reporting the adverse effects resulting from the use of
             medicines and pharmaceutical products or any other medical related problem. Also, she trained
             students about ways for these reporting tasks to the Egyptian Pharmaceutical Vigilance Center
             (EPVC) of the Egyptian Drug Authority (EDA).
             The other part of the day included awareness activities performed by the attended university
             students  who  educated  other  university  staff  and  students  about  this  concept  and  reporting
             mechanisms.


































































             24    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Activities & Achievements

              The First Students Scientific Day


             The Faculty of Pharmacy held on Tuesday, March 7  2023, the activities of “the first student
                                                                   th
             scientific  day”,  under  the  Patronage  of  Prof.  Cherif  Khater  (University  President),  under
             supervision of Assoc. Prof. Ahmed Ramadan ElSheakh - program director - and Dr. Bassant
             Maher, with the presence of  Programs Directors : Prof. Dr. Amira Taman, Prof. Dr. Noha Al-
             Wasifi - and Asst. Prof.  Ihab Abdel Hay and Prof. Dr. Rania Al-Shahini - Professor at the College
             of  Pharmacy.

             During the day, 11 MNU pharmacy scientific students introduced various scientific topics that
             have been discussed and evaluated by a specialized committee of MNU professors.
             The  day  objectives  were  to  disseminate  the  scientific  information  searched  by  the  students,
             strengthen their presentation, communication, and research skills, added to discover students’
             talents, abilities, and creativity in the research field.
             Those students were:

             - Hossny Mohamed Abdelhafez
             - Yasmeen Ahmed Elagamy Sakrana

             - Hana Tarek Elsaed khodir
             - Shrook Mohamed Elsaid Abdullah

             - Nada Mohammed Ismail Mohammed
             - Aseel Mohammed Elsayed Hassan

             - Sara Mohammed mansour abdelgawad
             - Raghad kandil fathy Elsayed

             - Amira Mosaad Aboelftouh
             - Malak Hisham Ibrahim

             - Farah Hamdy Meki




































                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Chapter III

             Student Activities in the Pharmacognosy Term II, 2022/2023


             Under the supervision of Dr. Yehia Amin, assistant professor of pharmacognosy MNU Faculty
             of Pharmacy, who asked to design herbal products that work as laxatives or topical ones for
             rheumatism  and  circulatory  problems. The  students  searched  the  data  and  gathered  different
             herbal products together in one product with guessing the suitable price for this and, they also
             clarified the uses of each ingredient ,depending on their educational knowledge, to form  the uses
             of each ingredient to form a final product with the needed indications.

             The faculty students demonstrated wonderful fulfillment and their activities were collected in
             one book as illustrated.








































































             26    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Activities & Achievements

             Signed Protocols and Partnerships

             In the first year of the MNU Faculty of Pharmacy

             The Faculty of Pharmacy at Mansoura National University signed a cooperation protocol with
             the Egyptian Drug Authority (EDA) on 1  February 2023. The protocol aimed at developing the
                                                      st
             skills of students and graduates and providing them with the necessary skills and competencies
             to keep pace with the requirements of the local and global labor market and contribute to the
             development of the professional path.
             Assoc. Prof. Ahmed Ramadan ElSheakh - Director of the PharmD Program - Clinical Pharmacy at
             the MNU Faculty of Pharmacy signed the protocol on the part of Mansoura National University,
             and Prof. Dr. Ayman Al-Khatib - EDA Vice President on the EDA side, in the presence of Dr. Rasha
             Ziadeh - Assistant to the President of the Commission for Technical Development and Capacity
             Development, and Dr. Walid Amir - Faculty of Pharmacy at Mansoura National University.

             Signing  of  the  protocol  comes  within  the  framework  of  the  faculty’s  vision  on  raising  the
             professional,  scientific,  and  research  level  of  their  students,  preparing  trained  cadres  at  the
             highest level, qualifying them for the labor market, and providing them with the expertise and
             skills  necessary  to  keep  pace  with  global  developments  in  the  field  of  pharmaceuticals.






























             https://www.mansnu.edu.eg/news-ar/2023-02-01-16-32-38






















                          Keep tuned with the upcoming cooperation protocols.



                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Chapter IV]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Student





                                                                      H onor





                                                                      B oard]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Chapter IV

             The top ten ranked students for the first semester 2022/2023






























                    Pharmacy students who won the Ramadan Religious

             Competition at the university level that was held in Ramadan

                                                         2023




















































             30    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Student Honor Board

                    Congratulations for pharmacy students for achieving

                                     positions at the Student Union



















                 Nada Sameh Ali        Rawan moheb El-shafey    Bilal Kadry El-Sayed     Elsayed Hossam Gaber
                     Co-president             President              Higher Committee          Member


















               Ahmed Sameh Ramadan        Fatma Gamal Eid       Hager Gamal Mohamed      Mennatollah Mohamed
                      Member                  Member                   Member                  Member


















              Mohamed Shaher Mohamed     Radwa Wael Gouda          Hossny Mohamed Abdelhafez          Hanaa Mohamed El-morsy
                      Member                  Member                   Member                  Member


















                                                    Mohamed Mohsen Tawfik
                                                           Member
                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Editorial Board










                                 Editorial Board





                                                   Editor in Chief
                                                      Assoc.Prof. Ahmed R ElSheakh


                                                   Editor
                                                      Assoc.Prof. Yhiya Amen
                                                      Dr. Bassant Maher
                                                      Dr. Randa Hani
                                                      Dr. Eman Yosrey



                                                   Graphic Design
                                                      Hamada Hamdy


                                                   Thanks To Our Students:

                                                     Assistant Content Editors
                                                      Ahmed Abdallah Elsebaey
                                                        Mariam Maher Mohamed
                                                      Mohamed shaher Mohamed
                                                       Ahmed Sameh Mohamed

                                                     Video Editors
                                                      Rehab Ehab Elmamlouk
                                                      Nada sameh ali tag
                                                        Samia Raed Mohammed Samy
                                                      Nour Mohamed mounir
                                                      Radwa wael awad gouda























             32    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Acknowledgment













                     Special Thanks





                                       Special Thanks for Faculty Staff :


                                          - Prof. Rania El Shahiny

                                          - Dr. Ghada EL Emam
                                          - Dr. Yhiya Amen

                                          - Dr. Yousra EL Far
                                          - Dr. Samar Samir

                                          - Dr. Noha Osama Mansour
                                          - Dr. Bassant Maher

                                          - Dr. Walid Amir
                                          - Dr. Hamed EL Shafey

                                          - Dr. Abdullah Haikal
                                          - Dr. Randa Hany

                                          - Dr. Eman yosry
                                          - Dr. Amgad Salem

                                          - Dr. Yomna EL Lethi
                                          - Dr. Badeaa Zakaria

                                          - Dr. Diaa Fakhry
                                          - Dr. Shreen Nabwi

                                          - Dr. Kareem El Meadawie
                                          - Mr. Amir Philip






















                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Faculty Strategy






                                                   Leadership  and  innovation  in  pharmaceutical

                  VISION                           education, training, scientific research, and community
                                                   service  within  the  framework  of  sustainable
                                                   development to reach a prominent position regionally
                                                   and  internationally  in  the  field  of  pharmacy.













                                                   Our goal is to prepare qualified pharmacists regionally
                                                   and internationally, following the latest scientific and
                                                   professional standards that are commensurate with the

                  MISION                           needs of the labor market and the scientific community.
                                                   We aim to instill the values and ethics of the pharmacy
                                                   profession  while  enabling  our  graduates  to  compete
                                                   and  keep  pace  with  scientific  and  technological
                                                   developments to raise the efficiency of the treatment
                                                   system and achieve sustainable growth.








                                                   1- Supporting and developing the education, learning,
                                                      and student support system.

                                                   2- Developing the capabilities of the college’s human
                                                      resources  from  faculty  members,  assistant  staff,
                                                      technicians,  and  administrative  staff.

                                                   3- Preparing distinguished graduates who can compete,
                  STRATEGIC                           link  them  to  the  college,  and  meet  the  needs  of
                                                      the  labor  market  while  supporting  the  goals  of
                  GOALS                               sustainable  development.


                                                   4- Maximizing community participation and building
                                                      local and international partnerships.

                                                   5- Establishing an applied scientific research system
                                                      and  constantly  strengthening  it.

                                                   6-Sustaining  the  infrastructure  and  developing  the
                                                      college’s  resources.





             34    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Student Honor Board





























































































                                                                                         Vol. 1 - Issue 1 35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Arabic Version Coming Soon





























































                                            Faculty Of Pharmacy Mansoura National University



                                        ﺔـﻴﻠﻫﻷﺍ ﺓﺭﻮـﺼﻨﻤﻟﺍ ﺔـﻌـﻣﺎﺟ - ﺔـﻟﺪــﻴﺼﻟﺍ ﺔـﻴﻠﻛ
                                        FACULTY OF PHARMACY - MANSOURA NATIONAL UNIVERSITY



















                       ﺔﻴﻠﻬﻗﺪﻟﺍ ﺔﻈﻓﺎﺤﻣ - ﺔﺼﻤﺟ ﺔﻨﻳﺪﻣ - ﻮﻳﺎﻣ 15 ﺔﻘﻄﻨﻣ - ﻲﻠﺣﺎﺴﻟﺍ ﻲﻟﻭﺪﻟﺍ ﻖﻳﺮﻄﻟﺍ

                       International Coastal Road - 15  of May District - Gamasa City - Dakahlia Governorate
                                                  th
                                                    phdclinical@mansnu.edu.eg]]></page></pages></Search>